<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>the Glory of God is man fully alive - Irenaeus on Traveling Beard</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in the Glory of God is man fully alive - Irenaeus on Traveling Beard</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://travelingbeard.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Raindrop</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2019-01-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2019-01-19/</guid><description>Ashlee and I have been married nearly 5 years. Having been single for the previous 33 years I related to the world, to grief, to joy, to music, to travel, to career from a very isolated framework. I have always thought myself generous, caring, and aware of the needs of others. However, I began to realize how selfish I had been. The initial months and even first year of marriage were a shock to my system(physically and mentally).</description></item><item><title>knock, knock; Sufjan again...</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2018-04-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2018-04-15/</guid><description>So apparently the only thing I’m able to write about are the words and lyrics of Sufjan Stevens. Listening to The Only Thing today. Sufjan wrote this album in response to events unfolding in his own family. However specific he intended this to be today what struck me was the ‘Perseus aligned with the skull` that made me pull up the lyrics and give them a more thorough read. My interpretation was viewed through the lens of spiritual relationship with Christ, so I thought at first he was relating this to Golgotha.</description></item><item><title>Friday Memories</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2017-08-04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2017-08-04/</guid><description>I’ve listened to a lot of Sufjan over the years so it’s no surprise that at certain points his music triggers memories of past experiences. Today his song ‘Futile Devices’ took me back to a long drive that was a particularly unique moment of serenity and peace. Lightening flashes danced in the distance, wind rushing by with the windows down, music cranked up and a friend along for the ride. Almost two hours of sitting, watching, and listening.</description></item><item><title>Adventure Car Saga</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2017-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2017-07-03/</guid><description>I don’t think you can consider buying up cheap old weird cars as a hobby. However I’ve spent an extreme amount of time pursuing this endeavor. So with some examination I’ve been coming to terms with the possibility that I don’t actually enjoy restoring old cars. I enjoy driving them and I enjoy occasionally working on them because old cars always need work. I’ve been trying to ask myself a few questions about my car…obsession.</description></item><item><title>Route 66 Butterscotch Soda</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2017-05-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2017-05-10/</guid><description>Well, here we are again. A few years later and another trip to check out a Subaru in California. This time I’m headed to SoCal and I’ve lined up a few stops for the trip home on I-40 and RT66. I’ve got 1600+ miles to cover and 23+ hours of driving ahead of me before my feet are back on the Barbarossa.
My plans are to check out
Wigwam Village #7 Cool Springs Gas Station Barringer Meteorite Crater 66 Diner Blue Swallow Motel Blue Hole of Santa Rosa I’ll be headed east in an 82 Subaru Wagon in less than 24 hours.</description></item><item><title>I believe Lord, help my unbelief</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2016-03-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2016-03-10/</guid><description>Trust…trust…are you getting it yet? TRUST!
Seems like such a simple concept to continually fail to realize into practice. Mark 9:14-29 mentions a man who came to Jesus with a son that needed healing and the father says to Jesus, “But if You can do anything, take pity on us and help us!” Christ responds and the man responds again, “I do believe, help my unbelief.” In my life that statement is full of meaning and could look something like this.</description></item><item><title>I've just had an apostrophe</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2016-01-06/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2016-01-06/</guid><description>Today is the day traditionally celebrated as Epiphany in remembrance of Christ’s manifestation to the world. Most often associated to the visit of the Magi; Casper, Melchior, and Balthasar, but for others it may be associated with Christ’s baptism in the Jordan. Some call it Three Kings day, but I think the Dutch and German’s have the market cornered on cool names for the day; Driekoningen or Dreikönigstag. In some countries groups of young people called Sternsinger (star singers – how cool is that) travel from door to door singing songs and blessing homes.</description></item><item><title>Test of Manhood &amp; proof of foolishness</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2015-07-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2015-07-15/</guid><description>This is a manly post about manly things and manly feelings. When you’re a man you do manly things like grow a beard, fix broken stuff and on occasion light things on fire. Tonights manly situations include a manly chainsaw and manly work outside followed by a manly test.
My friend helped me cut trees tonight to clear out the area where I’ll be building a house. A few hours of intense log cutting, dragging and experimenting with precisely felling trees and we threw in the towel with the failing light.</description></item><item><title>Jitterbugs</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2015-06-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2015-06-03/</guid><description>I leave early in the morning for Reno! The last time I flew across the country to pickup a car and drive it home I wasn’t the slightest bit nervous, but I probably should have been. It’s strange that this time when I’m more prepared that I’m definitely more jittery and anxious about the trip. Even just packing my bags today I can sense it. It’s been a while since I ventured out on something without any clue what will happen.</description></item><item><title>You’re doing what…again?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2015-05-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2015-05-01/</guid><description>Yes exactly I’m doing it again. 2500+ miles in a worn out old Subaru.
[picture of quincy roo]
This time I’ll be flying out to Reno to pick up an 82 GL wagon near Quincy California. I’ll never be able to quite replace RubySu, but for as cheap as I bought this car it’s a good start. She may not look like much, but it’s a California car so I don’t expect much/any rust beyond the rear panel.</description></item><item><title>We made it</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-10-12/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-10-12/</guid><description>It’s not too many people that get to have their second honeymoon before they’ve been married for a year. Of course it’s not many people that break down in their 33 year old Subaru wagon in the middle of Nebraska, sell it on the spot and have their mother give them a ride home from their first honeymoon either. This trip was rather less eventful then the last attempt. We rented a Mazda from Thrifty that we’ve dubbed “Tiny Van” (must be said in the Fat Albert voice) and decided to revisit beautiful Kearney, Nebraska on the way.</description></item><item><title>Great Scott!</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-08-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-08-14/</guid><description>Tonight Ashlee and I had one of the most hilarious experiences I can remember. We went downtown for the movies in the park summer series where they had a free drive-in showing of Back to the Future. After the movie was over everyone was starting to pack up and head out. Since we weren’t in any rush we hadn’t packed up our blanket yet, but quite a few people had already left.</description></item><item><title>Bittersweet Farewell</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-06-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-06-03/</guid><description>The day finally came to let an old friend pass on. I don’t think it’s really sunk in yet. I haven’t had a car more memorable and fun in my whole life. I first drove her home at 55mph from Denver in a 15 hour straight shot. Your name (a bit of a misnomer) was lovingly given by friends. Together we spent blustery winter nights plowing through new snow. She put the best 4x4s to shame.</description></item><item><title>Book the First</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-05-21/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2014-05-21/</guid><description>“When I first met Belloc he remarked to the friend who introduced us that he was in low spirits. His low spirits were and are much more uproarious and enlivening than anybody else’s high spirits. He talked into the night; and left behind in it a glowing track of good things. When I have said that I mean things that are good, and certainly not merely bons mots, I have said all that can be said in the most serious aspect about the man who has made the greatest fight for good things of all the men of my time.</description></item><item><title>A bit of Ketchup…er Katsup</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-12-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-12-01/</guid><description>Well I’ve been pretty terrible at updating lately. So I’ve thrown together some of the major events from the last 6 months. There’s a whole new world of adventure waiting for me.</description></item><item><title>King of the Mountain</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-07-13/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-07-13/</guid><description>Right after Cisco Live I packed the car and headed out for Colorado. I loaded up the tent, sleeping bag, backpack, and general provisions for driving a 30+ year old car a long distance. Honestly I’m pretty impressed that RubySu and I made it all the way out to Pike’s Peak and back. When driving an old and somewhat sketchy car your expectations and plans have to be pretty flexible. You’re encouraged to pull off to the side to take in the scenery…while the car cools down for a bit.</description></item><item><title>Year of the Beard</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-04-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-04-19/</guid><description>I’ve grown facial hair for a long time. I’ve had big civil war style muttonchops, giant goatees, mustaches of various successes, hipster hawks and soul patches. No matter what though the beard always reappears. For some time I’d wondered how long I could grow a beard without any trimming in a single year. Then in November of 2011 a situation came up and the only way I knew how to respond to it was to shave my head and beard.</description></item><item><title>Rally America 2013 100 Acre Woods Rally</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-02-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2013-02-18/</guid><description>This is my first attempt to provide a Rally Guide for spectators of the 100 Acre Woods Rally. I hope this information can be used to help plan your trip, set your expectations and familiarize you with the area.
This event happens around the third weekend in February and is part of the national Rally America circuit. People come from as far away as Michigan, New York and Texas just to be a spectator for this event.</description></item><item><title>One Year Ago or This S*** Sucks</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-12-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-12-24/</guid><description>One year ago I had this to say, “I’m looking forward to this Christmas as well as the new year. I’m content and hopeful and encouraged and ready to see what will happen this next year.” If I had known then what I know now I’d have probably hidden out under a rock to let the year pass by and come out again like Rip Van Winkle. I can’t remember a worst year in the entire Book of Eli.</description></item><item><title>Made it...well mostly</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-12-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-12-18/</guid><description>Drove something like 2500 miles, had my car broken into in Seattle, snowboarded in Grand Targahee, visited like 20 autoparts stores, almost broke down in the middle of nowhere, got mystery barista’s phone number, had a box for a car window, was profiled by the Colorado State Patrol(but let go), crossed two more states off my list, and the car broke down like two blocks from my parents house. All in all a decent trip.</description></item><item><title>You’re doing what?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-11-27/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-11-27/</guid><description>Yes exactly.
I’m driving a 31 year old Subaru Wagon literally half the way across the country, over mountain passes during snow season. Well at least I will be once Saturday gets here. My route is still to some degree entirely dependent on weather conditions, but I suppose that’s part of the adventure. I’m excited to visit Montana for the first time and Coeur d’Alene certainly has a cool name. I may just discover and be accepted into a tribal culture of sasquatch near Yellowstone never to return to civilization.</description></item><item><title>wise words</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-11-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-11-05/</guid><description>Alexander Hamilton said, “A nation which can prefer disgrace to danger is prepared for a master, and deserves one.”</description></item><item><title>Anyone want a Honda Civic</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-10-30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-10-30/</guid><description>Damn civic.
I fix you up; replace your struts, wheel rotors, suspension bushings, upper control arm and ball joints, lower ball joints, and get you brand new tires. I then get your door fixed which only went awry because of being up on the jack for all this other stuff. Then I get you back from the body shop and you repay me with running like crap. So I replace your distributor and rotor bug, try to get you to relearn your idle after reseting the ECM/PCM and still no love.</description></item><item><title>When it hits the fan</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-10-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-10-22/</guid><description>What a week. I’ll refrain from giving the specifics of the biggest event and just say that God came through when no other solution was possible. Monday after a weekend of work some things came up that I guess I didn’t think much of at the time, but ended up being quite a big deal. I knew better and yet put myself in a difficult situation by the actions I chose to take during our weekend work.</description></item><item><title>Seattle and a good old fashioned house burning</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-09-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-09-30/</guid><description>Not very talkative tonight, but here’s a couple cool galleries. The first is my friend’s house burning down, but don’t worry it was on purpose.
[pictures of house burning] [video of house burning trogdor]
And this one is from Seattle.
[pictures from seattle]</description></item><item><title>Eli ‘time traveling beard’ Barb</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-07-14-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-07-14-02/</guid><description>So apparently I’ve discovered time travel and went back to Shenandoah Valley in the 1800s. I’ll bet the beard helped me blend right in with the locals. Though I guess I didn’t think it was worth coming back to the future once I’d gone to the past. I’m even married so there’s that to look forward to. I hope she has all her teeth.</description></item><item><title>Many Shades of Black</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-07-14-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-07-14-01/</guid><description>A quick shout out to Benchmark Appraisal in Springfield, MO for making this possible. You suck.</description></item><item><title>Just Because</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-07-12-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-07-12-01/</guid><description>[picture of Fiat with mutemath or die]</description></item><item><title>A tale of two cities</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-30/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-30/</guid><description>I came across my favorite new menacing quote the other day in Dickens’ A Tale of two cities. Frankly I’m amazed that I’ve never heard it reused in any Westerns.
“For I’m the devil at quick mistakes, and when I make one it takes the form of lead”</description></item><item><title>When the moon hits your eye</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-27/</guid><description>Lately I’ve been hitting the streets during the late hours to get in a few miles on my bike. You might think this is a bit crazy, but so far I’ve found that the later that I go that the safer I feel. Traffic at 11:00pm on the secondary streets is much lower than during the day and after 1:00am is almost non-existent even on the main roads. That late at night the weather is perfect for riding too because the heat of the day is over and it has had a chance to cool off allowing for a rather pleasant ride.</description></item><item><title>Johnny Popper and Ms. Allis</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-09/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-09/</guid><description>Friday Dad and I were moving tractors around to free up some room in their carport for my newest family member Lemondrop. Amazingly enough Dad has the magical touch and we almost almost had the John Deere started just from cranking over the flywheel. Close, but no cigar though and we ended up having to pull it out with the Allis and pop the clutch while being towed to get it going.</description></item><item><title>Utah…t you tah a Fiat?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-08/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-06-08/</guid><description>7 states + 2534 miles + 94 hours + 60 mph + 172.19 Gallons at 616.44 dollars + 4 nights sleeping outside + 5 bags of pistacchios + 1 tow bar + 2 beards =1974 Fiat 128
From June 2-6 I drove out to Salt Lake City and back to pickup another Fiat 128. I already had some vacation time saved up that I needed to use or lose and this car popped up a couple months ago so this was as good an opportunity as any to travel a bit, visit a couple states I haven’t been to before and pickup another Fiat.</description></item><item><title>The Dark Horse won at Queen City Beard and Mustache Championship</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-04-21/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-04-21/</guid><description>I beard…a lot, but tonight I received the shock and joy of a beardtime(lifetime) when I won first place in the Queen City Beard and Mustache championship in the ‘full beard’ category. I really can’t believe it still because there were so many other incredible beards up in that category. There was a guy with a kilt and a massive Braveheart beard, a guy with a beard down to his belt line, a Dos XX guy too and dozens more with just straight up incredible beards.</description></item><item><title>Rally America – 100 Acre Woods 2012</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-03-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-03-01/</guid><description>Dad and I spent Friday and Saturday watching the Rally in the woods up near Salem Missouri. Fortunately this year there weren’t torrential rains ahead of the rally and we were able to see stages on both days…and we also didn’t break down in the Fiat this year either so that was an added bonus. My respect for Ken Block continues to increase because of his willingness to participate in this rally whenever he gets the opportunity.</description></item><item><title>Peoples is peoples</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-24/</guid><description>In the comments someone wrote this, which I thought displayed Pete’s sentiments exactly. Translation: “Take a place like NYC.﻿ Lots of people, right? Living life and working their jobs. But the city isn’t alive. People being there makes it alive, and people are pretty much alike everywhere. Not like architecture, which is very different everywhere. Like tomatoes–no two are identical, but they’re all tomatoes. Life is dancing, and music, and fun, but also doing mundane things–and everyone has a balance of fun things and tedious things.</description></item><item><title>Copeland</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-14/</guid><description>On this day of love or day of sadness depending on your current status I wanted to revisit one of the best bands for either condition on this day. I can remember the first Copeland show I went to; it was up in Kansas City at some little crappy venue where they played with Lovedrug and Veda. This would have been during the era of their first album Beneath the Medicine Tree.</description></item><item><title>Houstonia</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-12-02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-12-02/</guid><description>“The great misfortune is that a notion obtains with those in power that the world, or the people, require more governing than is necessary. To govern well is a great science, but no country is ever improved by too much governing…most men think when they are elevated to position that it requires an effort to discharge their duties and they leave common sense out of the question.” Sam Houston
“Govern wisely, and as little as possible.</description></item><item><title>Somethings get better with age</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-12-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-02-12-01/</guid><description>In particular the old western spoof, Rustler’s Rhapsody, from the mid 80s. The two sidekicks Jim and Jud, played by Bran Von Hoffman and Christopher Malcom, deliver some of my favorite straight faced, matter of fact, droll punchlines. These types of minor characters don’t often get much attention, but they really add a lot of depth to the film. Here’s a few of their lines
Colonel Ticonderoga: You missed! How could you miss?</description></item><item><title>Collision</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-01-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-01-30/</guid><description>You can keep your picture perfect life. Keep your lies and see if I care. I’m not the one you’re fooling. Clean the outside of the cup and ignore the death you’re drinking. Oblivious to the blood on our hands. Go ahead and wipe that smudge from your face.
You tread your freedom underfoot and so bind yourself. Indulgence is your pleasure. Why should you restrain yourself. Dive in to the pool of destruction.</description></item><item><title>O’Hare O’Hare have my Starbucks gone?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-01-18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-01-18/</guid><description>So what would you do with a 5 hour layover in Chicago? Play Angry Birds, maybe watch a movie, go grab a bite to eat, or check your Facebook and update twitter? Well today my status updates/check-ins would have been something like this.
Checking in at E1 B14? – Bingo there’s a Starbucks B5 was before B9 K4 Kato, watch out for Inspector Clouseau G14; my first co-conspirator, that dude was rad H1=Coolest peeps in Chicago F9…disappeared, there’s not a Starbucks here.</description></item><item><title>Zelda Step</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-01-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2012-01-11/</guid><description>So I’m pretty new to dubstep in general. I’m not sure I even would have given it much of a chance had I not already been listening a bunch to Daft Punk’s Tron soundtrack which is in a similar vein though I don’t think is technically dubstep. For those of you so new you don’t know what that is, hey no diggs I was there too, its a rhythmic, bass laden, electronicly derived music genre very popular with house music hipsters, DJs, and geeks.</description></item><item><title>Merry Christmas</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-24/</guid><description>Sufjan put out a video a few years ago with his Christmas albums and I just randomly rediscovered it on my Mom’s Mac today. Which was quite the coincidence because some friends of mine were just talking about his Christmas albums last night. It also truly feels like Christmas is here now after watching Chevy Chase and Christmas Vacation. I love the movie, but I’m not sure I’ve ever had such a good time watching it as I did the other night.</description></item><item><title>10 acres of quiet contemplation</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-09/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-09/</guid><description>This summer I bought 10 acres on FR 45 between FR 120 and 116 just west of Bois D’Arc. For anyone curious the French translation of the name Bois d’Arc is “wood of the bow”. Bois D’Arc also known as the Osage Orange is one of the best woods for making a long bow.
Now that I have some land I’m one step closer to being able to start on a number of things I’ve really wanted to for a while.</description></item><item><title>Fiery Italian….where’s mine?…um the car I mean</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-07/</guid><description>Fiat has a pretty seductive commercial for the new Abarth 500 coming to the states in 2013. For the extra Italian flair you could refer to it as the Abarth Cinquecento(pronounce Chean Qwe Chentoe) Here’s a rough translation:
What are you looking at? Uh!? What are you looking at?! (slap) Are you undressing me with your eyes? Poor guy…you can’t help it? Is your heart beating? Is your head spinning? Do you feel lost thinking that I could be yours forever?</description></item><item><title>Fast Cars and Loud Music</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-12-05/</guid><description>and also curvy roads can be great medication. Not lasting, as nothing in this world is meant to be, but fitting for the right moment to let out pent up energy and simultaneously fill you back up with energy. Also encouraging when you meet a like minded spirit to whom even in defeat you can wave to and acknowledge you both hold on to something much deeper than win or loss in a drag race, but that you’re both there to drive.</description></item><item><title>GKC is my peeps</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-30/</guid><description>For when he who doubts can only say, ‘I do not understand,’ it is true that he who knows can only reply or repeat, ‘You do not understand.’ And under that rebuke there is always a sudden hope in the heart; and the sense of something that would be worth understanding.</description></item><item><title>Sometimes I go opposite</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-28/</guid><description>No shave November this year took a slightly different course for me. To some degree I wear this hairy visage as a testament that I stand out from the crowd so I suppose it is only fitting that while the world turns one way that I should turn another. The beard is gone. Impressive as it was this time and even though I’m normally nearly a spokesperson for beardedness it is a fitting change at this moment for more reasons then I care to delve into.</description></item><item><title>You don’t know how many times</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-18/</guid><description>[xkcd wisdom of the ancients] You don’t know how many times this scenario has happened to me. Oh XKCD you see to the root of me.</description></item><item><title>ps 86</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-17/</guid><description>Hear, O Lord, and answer me, for I am poor and needy. Guard my life, for I am devoted to you. You are my God; save your servant who trusts in you. Have mercy on me, O Lord for I call to you all day long. Bring joy to your servant, for to you, O Lord, I lift up my soul.</description></item><item><title>Aish Tamid</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-11-16/</guid><description>Matisyahu came and performed tonight in Springfield at the Gillioz Theatre. It was a low key night as he was only accompanied on guitar by Adam Weinberg who is really quite a phenomenal guitarist. I’ve listened to Matisyahu a bit over the last few years, but getting to see him in person allows a chance to see beyond just the music and get an idea in small degree of who he is.</description></item><item><title>Life as I know it</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-10-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-10-17/</guid><description>Some times living life single is filled with contentment and can be far preferable to being attached. Then at other times it can feel overwhelmingly daunting and the weight almost unbearable. How close these moments seem to follow one another is strange indeed. One minute I’m able to appreciate how truly free and unencumbered my life is unattached and I rejoice greatly for the joy of being adaptable and able to change direction in a moments notice.</description></item><item><title>MuteMath - Little Rock</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-10-15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-10-15/</guid><description>Earlier this week I drove down to Little Rock to catch MM again on their Odd Soul tour at the Revolution Music Room. At the show I met a couple of people who of all things are friends with Joe Copeland. As we talked a bit more we found out that each of us had been at the same show back in 2006 at Remingtons in Springfield which was the first time I’d ever even heard of them let alone seen them.</description></item><item><title>Speaking In Riddles</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-30/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-30/</guid><description>All that is gold does not glitter, Not all those who wander are lost; The old that is strong does not wither, Deep roots are not reached by the frost. From the ashes a fire shall be woken, A light from the shadows shall spring; Renewed shall be blade that was broken, The crownless again shall be king. Fellowship of the Ring – JRR Tolkien
I will open my mouth in a parable; I will utter dark sayings of old, Psalm 78:2</description></item><item><title>Sunday Afternoon Videos</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-25/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-25/</guid><description>In July 2008 I took a spin around the Eiffel Tower. It took me about 15 minutes to walk down from the middle platform. I’ve sped this video up a bit, but you get the idea.
[video]
This year for the Fourth of July we had some spare black powder that didn’t get used so we decided to have some fun with it.
[video]
And finally some videos from the 2010 100 Acre Woods Rally up near Salem Missouri.</description></item><item><title>Murder By Death it is...</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-22/</guid><description>at least for New Years Eve and not just my guess in a game of Clue. It’s been a while since I’ve been to Chicago and last year was the first in about 5 or 6 years that I didn’t do a rock show trip on the eve of a new year. After having gone to see Band of Horses the previous 3 years in Atlanta I was ready for a switch up and had planned on seeing the Avett Bros, but somewhere along the way I decided against that.</description></item><item><title>Copeland</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-09-19/</guid><description>Good music is indeed timeless. I’ll forget about a band for a time and then rediscover them only just at the right time to have a companion to see me through some particularly difficult time. It means a lot to have something to take your mind off the present situation and hearing a song written thousands of miles away or years in the past that some how shares in or addresses some current situation just drives home how common our struggles are.</description></item><item><title>A Day in the Life of</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-28/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-28/</guid><description>Here’s an article I recently wrote for another blog I contribute to on Tuesdays.
Ivan Denisovich Shukov is a character in a novel by Russian author Alexsander Solzhenitsyn. Denisovich was a laborer in a work camp in post World War 2 Russia that was taken in part from some of the real life experiences that Solzhenitsyn had himself while living in the Russian gulags and work camps. We get to see one single day in the life of this prisoner during the course of the book.</description></item><item><title>ban·der·snatch</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-25/</guid><description>In a letter from May 15, 1966, C.S. Lewis wrote “No one ever influenced Tolkien–you might as well try to influence a bandersnatch.”
I heard this recently while listening to a lecture discussing the friendship between Tolkien and Lewis and it just made me snicker so much that I had to find out what a bandersnatch was.
ban·der·snatch
an imaginary wild animal of fierce disposition. a person of uncouth or unconventional habits, attitudes, etc.</description></item><item><title>Atypical women I have known</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-24/</guid><description>Of all the women I’ve known so far the writings and impact of two continue to amaze me. One an acquaintance and the other a close friend.
I met Heather way back in 2005 when I was keeping a Xanga blog. Through the Xanga Springfield crowd I stumbled across her musings and was just completely floored. I thought to myself I’ve got to figure out a way to meet this girl.</description></item><item><title>Hallelujah</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-08-23/</guid><description>I just found this in my documents on my Mac tonight. I apparently wrote it back in May 2006 even before my niece was actually born. The piece is satisfying in it’s simplicity.
Hallelujah Hallelujah for my friends Hallelujah for my best friend’s wife getting a teaching job Hallelujah for a dad who stands for truth and righteousness even through adversity Hallelujah for my sister having a little girl Hallelujah for mercy Hallelujah for forgiveness Hallelujah for two great nephews Hallelujah for music to uplift my soul Hallelujah for a quiet house Hallelujah for my mom’s prayers Hallelujah for the cross Hallelujah for the cross Hallelujah for the cross Hallelujah for HE is Risen and alive Hallelujah for Christ’s love for me Hallelujah</description></item><item><title>Holy crap, holy crap, holy crap</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-07-18-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-07-18-02/</guid><description>They’re doing a new Muppet movie! It looks like they’ve done well with casting because they’ve got Jason Segel and Amy Adams, which I think will fit just right with their cornball comedic abilities. The storyline is to be based around the premise of reviving the old Muppet Theater for another performance. I hope they can tap in to the old school Muppet humor and presentation to bring back a little bit of the feeling that I think was lost when Jim Henson passed away.</description></item><item><title>The options are limitless</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-07-18-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-07-18-01/</guid><description>Keep this on the down low, but tonight I came across the biggest loophole ever. I’m not sure if this is something that society can tolerate or the law will even allow. It may just be the biggest scandal of all time. When given the option to include a monogram on a shirt or really anything…you can put whatever you want. No one will dare stop you. On a shirt you have 16 characters to do with as you please.</description></item><item><title>The Head and The Heart</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-06-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-06-22/</guid><description>It’s actually a band though not just any band, but likely to be the most up and coming group of the year with their beautiful melodies and simplistic presentation. There’s no pretentious hipster attitude about it. I read a comment from youtube that mentioned they were Seattle’s response to Mumford and Sons(M&amp;amp;S), a raw folky rock group from across the pond. Though I’ve yet to see M&amp;amp;S perform live I have seen The Head and The Heart(TH&amp;amp;TH) now and I don’t think it would be a stretch to say that Mr Mumford himself wouldn’t see this new young group as competition, but rather as complementary to his own outfit’s unique style.</description></item><item><title>Family and the Springs</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-06-21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-06-21/</guid><description>I recently went out to Colorado Springs with the family while Cassie was at camp Barnabas and though the drive was a bit long it was worth it. We spotted an old 70s Mazda RX-3 station wagon on the way out in a small junkyard and a huge salvage yard on the way back that I want to go back and spend some time in looking around. My friend Adam suggested spending as much time as possible in Garden of the gods while out there and I’ve got to say he was right on.</description></item><item><title>Past Waterdeep Shows</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-05-25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-05-25/</guid><description>Dec 11, 1992Hey RuthGusto&amp;rsquo;s Lawrence, KS
Mar 12, 1993Hey RuthGusto&amp;rsquo;s Lawrence, KS
May 15, 1993Hey RuthNew Earth Coffeehouse Kansas City, MO
Jul 23, 1994Whalebelly ExitThe Edge St. Louis, MO
Dec 3, 1994Hey Ruth, Whalebelly Exit, Don Chaffer &amp;amp; friendsNew Earth Coffeehouse Kansas City, MO
Feb 18, 1995Don &amp;amp; FriendsNew Earth Coffeehouse Kansas City, MO
Feb 20, 1995Don &amp;amp; Oren ThorntonNew Earth Coffeehouse Kansas City, MO
Apr 1, 1995Don Chaffer &amp;amp; friends (basically the original WD line-up w/ Lori added)Heart 2 Heart Lawrence, KS</description></item><item><title>Honda, truck, Fiat, Honda truck, hitchhike, push, walk, tow, Fiat, Honda</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-03-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-03-15/</guid><description>Well to be a traveling beard you have to do as the name implies, travel. As of late though my mode of transportation has been less than reliable from week to week. While battling problems with the Honda I’ve had to rely heavily upon the Fiat to fill in the gaps. However it has had it’s own problems too. We drove it up to watch the Rally races at the end of February in Salem, Rolla, Steelville area and she drove like a dream the whole way up.</description></item><item><title>Ramblings of a Single Dude</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-10-30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-10-30/</guid><description>Driving home tonight I started to consider single life and why I’m fine with it. At any point in time I can do whatever the hell I want.(Excuse the french, it’s only to emphasize the point) I can drive to KC or Asheville for a show, I can hop in my car and drive 130mph, I can work on whatever project I feel like, I am free to hang out with any one any where at any time.</description></item><item><title>WRC to Sufjan</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-02-08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-02-08/</guid><description>If the WRC came to the US where would an epic location be for it to be hosted? Grand Canyon? Tennessee/Kentucky hills? Death Valley? I feel like championing this cause, but if a bad location produces a poor turn out then that’s it. It’d be years before they even thought about trying it again. Could we even pull it off in the states? We already have so many spectator restrictions and low turn out(in comparison) for our Rally America that I can’t imagine we could produce a turn out for the international drivers that they’ve grown used to elsewhere.</description></item><item><title>Fiat Update</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-20/</guid><description>Well last weekend Dad and I started in on the Yugo to Fiat engine swap. We powered through until Sunday when we had to get the Fiat rolling so we could get it home and out of the way. Monday I got the water, electrical and gas all hooked up and flowing, but the carburetor is now the hurdle left to clear. Plus a few minor linkages for the accelerator that need fixed before she’ll be drivable.</description></item><item><title>Hipster Transformation Complete</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-13/</guid><description>I seem to keep slipping more and more into the grandpa fashions of today’s hipsters. It is an odd mix though because it seemed to happen rather naturally. My grandfathers old cardigan sweaters which have been in my closet for 10+ years without ever seeing the light of day were the first piece adopted. They have the ability of taking even the most stifling office work attire and softening it with a certain Mr Rogers appeal.</description></item><item><title>Quick GKC</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-06/</guid><description>You cannot grow a beard in a moment of passion. – G.K. Chesterton</description></item><item><title>Yugo Humor</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-03/</guid><description>A car this legendary doesn’t require anything to bolster its legacy and fasten its place in history, but so the automotive history books aren’t entirely filled with sorrow and lamentation when they speak about the Yugo, here are a few jokes.
Why is the Yugo’s rear window heated? To keep your hands warm in the winter while you push it.
How do you double the value of a Yugo? Put a gallon of milk in the back seat.</description></item><item><title>I go where Yugo</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2011-01-01/</guid><description>Quick update. I just recently acquired an old Yugo in a straight across the board trade for the 99 VW Jetta that I had sitting that could only drive in reverse(long story). A salvage yard in Topeka had posted it up for sale and when it didn’t meet the reserve on Ebay(it was only bid up to $300 and some change) I offered a trade. In my mind I was just ecstatic to be getting rid of this piece of crap VW and it’s frozen bolts around the transmission that have just been laughing at me.</description></item><item><title>Fiat Udate</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-09-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-09-22/</guid><description>So I’ve been meaning to give an update on the Fiat saga for a while. Late last December I went outside to start her up and she made a pretty heinous grinding noise when I turned over the key. I was thinking starter grind possibly as it still ran and didn’t sound rough so while curious about what on earth could possibly have made the noise I didn’t have time to check into it any further.</description></item><item><title>Holy hammhocks why do people have to be so difficult</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-09-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-09-02/</guid><description>Things are rarely as straight forward as we’d like them to be. I believe in absolutes, black and whites when it comes to matters of right and wrong, fundamental beliefs of faith and personal world views. But try as I may and as much as I want a single statement or a rigid response that I can use to apply to these disparate situations I encounter each day I’m left with none that cover every situation, that I can use applied in the same manner over and over again.</description></item><item><title>Oddities</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-03-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-03-15/</guid><description>I’ve been toodling around this site a bit tonight and came across a few pretty cool things I thought worth sharing. Most of this stuff I found at Design Verb
[pictures]
The full 365 day series of storm troopers can be seen @ this site</description></item><item><title>Average People</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-03-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-03-10/</guid><description>Got back late, late, late last night from Columbia. Cutler and I went up to see The Avett Brothers play at the Missouri Theater. Since I’ve really only listened to their most recent album it was cool to hear a much wider selection of their music in the show. They may be a bit too country/bluegrassy for some, but when they played they had that theater jumping. I mentioned to Cutler that there was a noticeably strong scent of hippie musk in the air, highlighted even more so by the people a few rows down lighting up.</description></item><item><title>100 Acre Woods Rally</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-02-28/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2010-02-28/</guid><description>Here’s a quick taste of what my dad and I went to see this weekend around the Salem Missouri area. This was the second race on the national Rally America circuit. The 100 Acre Woods Rally 2010. We met people in from northern Iowa, Fayetteville Arkansas, Oklahoma City, Minnesota and a few people from Springfield. I don’t think I’ve ever seen more rally wannabe Subarus parked in one place. I had to work hard not to have all wheel drive envy in my measly two-wheel drive civic.</description></item><item><title>For all you beardless saps</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-29/</guid><description>Mourn no more your un-woolen face. http://www.imadeyouabeard.com/</description></item><item><title>MuteMath Tulsa</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-27/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-27/</guid><description>Ventured down to Tulsa for another MuteMath show last Saturday with Kent and Robyn at Cain’s. I’d been to Cain’s before, but for some reason in my mind I had torn it down to a crappy old dancehall that wasn’t a very good venue. I guess I had some wires crossed because it was incredible. The crowd there was really into the show and really made the experience much more enjoyable then last week in KC.</description></item><item><title>The Issues – FotC</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-17-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-17-02/</guid><description>This just cracks me up. We watched a few Flight of the Conchords videos after house church the other night.
[Think about it video link]</description></item><item><title>MuteMath-KC</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-17-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-10-17-01/</guid><description>Holy frijoles what a good concert. Darren ended up crowdsurfing on top of his bass drum and playing off the rafters. Maybe slightly less energy than the last tour, but still all around a great show. Now to see them again in a couple of weeks in Tulsa with Kent and Robyn.
[mutemath KC pics]
Here’s a couple videos from the show. Sorry for the crappy audio, it was way overload for my camera.</description></item><item><title>It's Official</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-08-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-08-17/</guid><description>that I’ve been playing Rallisport Challenge 2 way too much on Xbox lately and it is beginning to effect my driving habits. I’m alive one more day in no small part thanks to the Lord’s great graciousness. He doesn’t always save us from our stupidity, but I’m sure thankful for those extremely noticeable times that he does. I came around a corner after coming up over a crest going about 50 or 55 that goes into a pretty decent little right turn.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to all things Scottish…</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-13-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-13-02/</guid><description>A bit of the Scottish Highland games from last year just outside of Fort Williams near Ben Nevis the tallest…hill in the UK.
[qt:http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/Caber-iPhone.m4v http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/Caber-poster.jpg 540 360]
[qt:http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/ThePipes-iPhone.m4v http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/ThePipes-poster.jpg 540 360]</description></item><item><title>Waterdeep in Tulsa</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-13-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-13-01/</guid><description>I found this video deeply embedded in my macbook so I dug it out, dusted it off and thought I’d share. Here they are Don and Lori Chaffer.
[qt:http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/Waterdeep1-iPhone.m4v http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/Waterdeep1-poster.jpg 540 360]
btw that video is finally iPhone compatible.</description></item><item><title>4th of July</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-09-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-09-02/</guid><description>And finally a clip from our Fourth of July. Kids don’t try this at home we’re trained idiots with no value for our own safety.
[qt:http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/4th-iPhone.m4v http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/fourthofjuly.jpg 540 360]
Click on the Picture to start the video.
We had a big cake called Ninjas of the Night that stopped after only a couple shots so we threw some black powder on it to tie it in with another one of our Comet Over America volleys.</description></item><item><title>A bunch of random things</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-09-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-07-09-01/</guid><description>A word about the new edition to my family. I flew out to Denver last Thursday to pick up my beautiful new baby Fiat. Well not exactly baby, she’s almost 37 years young. Actually I think her birthday from the manufacturer is coming up here shortly. A 1972 Fiat 128 with a whooping 50Hp in an 1100cc motor with only 78,000 miles and those cool tires are 1971 MOMO magnesium 13″ rims…I think they’re probably worth more than the car.</description></item><item><title>30 dead racoons…</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-29/</guid><description>I’m pretty sure that I saw at least that many on my way up to Iowa two weekends ago to see Chris and Kim. Iowa is slowly winning some ground with me. The area that they’re in is much nicer then where they’d lived before. We had a great time hanging out and talking. They’re both enjoying the area and I think it’s going to be a great place for them both.</description></item><item><title>Behold This Swarthy Face</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-24/</guid><description>So my dad passed on this wicked cool poem about beards that I thought I’d share with everyone. If you haven’t seen me lately my own beard is making quite a return though I think I’ll reign it in and keep it at the length of a 6 month beard.
Behold This Swarthy Face by Walt Whitman
Behold this swarthy face, these gray eyes, This beard, the white wool unclipt upon my neck, My brown hands and the silent manner of me without charm; Yet comes one a Manhattanese and ever at parting kisses me lightly on the lips with robust love, And I on the crossing of the street or on the ship’s deck give a kiss in return, We observe that salute of American comrades land and sea, We are those two natural and nonchalant persons.</description></item><item><title>Band of Horses!</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-22/</guid><description>So I got tickets a few months ago to a Band of Horses concert out at the Orange Peel in Ashville, NC. It’s about a twelve hour drive and I figured the open road would do me some good so I weaved in and out of the backroads and it ended up being more of a 14-16 hour drive over two days. I stopped over the first night in Elizabethtown, mainly because of the movie, to see what it was like.</description></item><item><title>A little over a year ago</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-06-21/</guid><description>It’s hard to believe that just a year ago I was on my first days walk out of Dublin just starting my travel. Not sure what importance or role that plays, but it’ll be cool this summer to think about “well about this time last year I was at such and such place”. Back at home now with my journal and pictures it’ll be nice to remember the fun times….and forget about those not so fun ones.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Day Madness</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-05-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-05-26/</guid><description>Wasabi mashed potatoes Grilled Corn on the Cob Grilled Fries Homemade Icecream Fresh Strawberries Angel food cake Smoked Salmon Brats We started fixing food at about 3:00 and people just started showing up in herds until we had a total of 23 people hanging out. We had croquette, scrabble, speedsbe(a new form of frisbe game), sidewalk chalk and even surrey rides. Who knew a rainy memorial day weekend could be so much fun.</description></item><item><title>Site upgrades or The adventure continues</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-05-09/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2009-05-09/</guid><description>Well it’s been a while and I’m a bit behind, but here’s a short update in pictures of how I spent my 2008 New Years Eve. Best New Years eve ever…even better than the one with my white polyester suit and sombraro. I’ll have additional updates shortly.</description></item><item><title>How will the escape begin?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-09-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-09-02/</guid><description>How will the escape begin?
A few years ago I wrote this onto the first page in my Bible. At the time I felt entangled in discouraging, defeating sin out of which I could not climb or struggle free. I also felt cut off, sitting on the cusp overlooking the next stage of my life, but powerless to join it or start it’s beginning. There was also my every day life that try my best I was only succeeding to show up for.</description></item><item><title>Nazareth?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-22/</guid><description>“Nazareth! Can anything good come from there?” Nathanael asked. “Come and see,” said Philip. When Jesus saw Nathanael approaching, he said of him, “Here is a true Israelite, in whom there is nothing false.” “How do you know me?” Nathanael asked. Jesus answered, “I saw you while you were still under the fig tree before Philip called you.” Then Nathanael declared, “Rabbi, you are the Son of God; you are the King of Israel.</description></item><item><title>Watch out flying nuns there’s a soaring beard in the air</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-18/</guid><description>So I went para-sailing while I was in Gimmelwald with Matt a guy I met from Texas and it was awesome. Afterwards we met up with some friends and went out to lunch where I had my first taste of horse steak. It was actually very good though I’m sure I should be put off by it.
[paragliding pics]</description></item><item><title>Israel, the bearded one cometh or mazel tov it’s a beard</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-13/</guid><description>Ok, so maybe it’s too early to say that I like it here, but I mean come on the facts are overwhelming.
Guys with big beards
Guys with cool hats
Guys with big beards and cool hats.
…oh yeah Christ, savior of mankind and Lord of Lords, born nearby. So you know there’s that.</description></item><item><title>Yodelehehoo</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-07/</guid><description>So I’ve been in Switzerland now for about 6 days and I’ve got another 5 left. I’ve spent the majority of my time, what will be nine days, at a great little village in the Alps called Gimmelwald at the Mountain Hostel. There’s a saying that they have here, “If heaven isn’t what it’s cracked up to be…send me back to Gimmelwald.” That might be a slight over statement, but it is definitely a very cool place.</description></item><item><title>In Honor of Aleksander Solzhenitsyn</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-08-04/</guid><description>Aleksander Solzhenitsyn – December 11, 1918 – August 3, 2008
Text of Address by
Alexander Solzhenitsyn
at Harvard Class Day Afternoon Exercises,
Thursday, June 8, 1978
I am sincerely happy to be here with you on this occasion and to become personally acquainted with this old and most prestigious University. My congratulations and very best wishes to all of today’s graduates.
Harvard’s motto is “Veritas.” Many of you have already found out and others will find out in the course of their lives that truth eludes us if we do not concentrate with total attention on its pursuit.</description></item><item><title>If you’re wondering Ninja Monkey translated to German is Ninja Monkeys</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-29/</guid><description>I had a great time in Nuremberg the past few days. I met some really cool guys to hang out with and see the city and I was able to visit Oma too. The city has 500,000 people, but still has a bit of a small town feeling. Will and I went out and saw the old Nazi rally grounds with the colliseum and the zeppelin field and then Chris and I went to check out the Palace of Justice Court Room 600 where the Nuremburg trials were held.</description></item><item><title>On Today’s Episode Pictorama or Pictacular, Pictacular are these words in your vernacular?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-25/</guid><description>So after spending an entire day on the train I was able to work on quite a few pictures to upload to the website. It may put you on picture overload, but here they are none the less. Separated by country. I’m in Nuremburg right now, because I decided to skip Frankfurt after seeing that the only two hostels I had listed which were very close to the train station were both in the red light district and while walking to the second I was offered to come inside and see something great…no thanks Frankfurt I’ll take my chances somewhere else.</description></item><item><title>1234… That’s the same combination of my luggage</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-21/</guid><description>Well it’s not quite that bad, but 0102 isn’t much better. And what is this number you ask? The code to the front door of my hostel tonight. Happy Belgian independence day by the way, living free since 1830. Tonight I’m “In Brugges” which is Dutch for flipping cool city! By far my favorite so far. Don’t know Dutch you say, or French or german? No problem because for the most part everyone is glad to speak English too.</description></item><item><title>Le Tour de France</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-16/</guid><description>Wow so my lifelong dream to see the Tour de France is now complete. I was at the first turn no more than 50 yards from the starting line to watch the beginning of the first stage of the Pyrenees in Toulouse France. The crowd was bustling with enthusiasm, fans from all over the world drape their flags over the barriers to the route and show their enthusiasm for their fellow countrymen competing, camera men everywhere and people pressed in to find a spot to catch a glimpse of the riders as they go by.</description></item><item><title>Chucks in Paris</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-13/</guid><description>On Beards —
The reaction for the most part is the same. Strange looks, whispers, rude youths hollering out as I walk by. These are par for the course of a true beardman. That said there are those experiences that make up in spades for them. In Edinburgh a young spanish couple had a boy no more than 3 or 4 years old who they couldn’t get to stop pointing, jumping, and yelling, “Barba, barba, barba, grande barba!</description></item><item><title>Paris Metro</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-12/</guid><description>Well the metro was about all of Paris that I got to see yesterday as I zipped back and forth trying to find a hostel that wasn’t all booked up. After 4-5 hours of riding the rails and looking hither and yon I finally gave up and just got a hotel room. Not as pricey as Belfast, but still not what I would have preferred. I had to stay in Paris last night because the train I had hoped to catch to Toulouse was all booked up as well because of the French Holiday on the 14th.</description></item><item><title>Paris on Friday</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-09-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-09-02/</guid><description>I got my rail pass in today from DHL [surprising I know since it came DHL ie. the suckiest delivery service ever.] and my flight is booked for Friday from Glasgow to Paris. Once I get there I’ll be trying as best I can to get to see a bit of the 2008 Tour de France during the Pyrenees stages near Toulouse in the south of France. Then back to Paris for a few days to see the Louvre and all kinds of stuff, maybe even Jim Morrison’s grave.</description></item><item><title>Murder by Death</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-09-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-09-01/</guid><description>The tension was so thick you could have cut it with a knife. Our group of rag tag rock and rollers had just found out some terrible news. Unfortunately because it was a dream I don’t quite remember what that news was, but we were mad and it was terrible and there in front of us were the people responsible. They were another rock band that was popular, but couldn’t rock their way out of a wet paper sack.</description></item><item><title>It’s not a question of where he grips it! It’s a simple question of weight ratios.</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-07/</guid><description>So this last week I was able to do quite a bit of fun stuff. I got to visit the William Wallace monument in Stirling which is quite impressive, visited Loch Ness and most importantly I got to visit Doune Castle. Doune is basically the most complete and well preserved example of a castle in the UK. But more importantly it was home to quite a few famous events. Including the ferocious taunting of the french knights and the grail shaped beacon of castle anthrax and finally the wedding scene of the king in the swamp.</description></item><item><title>Where were you when…</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-05/</guid><description>The one scripture that keeps coming to mind while I’ve been traveling has been in Job 38 where the Lord answers Job.
1.The the Lord answered Job out of the whirlwind and said, 2.Who is this that darkens counsel by words without knowledge? 3.Gird up now your loins like a man, and I will demand of you, and you declare to Me. 4.Where were you when I laid the foundation of the earth?</description></item><item><title>Trogdor Strikes Again!!</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-01-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-01-03/</guid><description>If you dare click on the mighty Trogdor!
[qt:http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/Trogdor.mov http://travelingbeard.com/wp-content/uploads/Trogdor-poster.jpg 500 240]</description></item><item><title>Great old cities and sites…but the trash</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-01-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-07-01-02/</guid><description>Let me just say for as much as the US has a long ways to go keeping our parks and cities free of trash, I guarantee you that we are lightyears ahead of the UK and Ireland.[I won’t make judgement yet against mainland Europe since I haven’t been there yet] It’s really shocking how in every green area, in every park, on every beach, along every street I find trash strewn about.</description></item><item><title>London Bridge is Falling Down</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-30/</guid><description>I spent a few days last week in and around London. I tried to get into Wimbledon, but I was number 9253 in the queue so I didn’t quite make it in. I also ventured up to Beaconsfield(pronounced Bekensfield) to the former home of GK Chesterton who is probably my favorite author. I’ve spent quite a bit of time here at the YWAM base camp in Scotland too hanging out with the whole crew here.</description></item><item><title>Mohair?</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-24/</guid><description>Here’s the last bit of my time in Ireland. I was in Cork for a couple days and then Doolin by the cliffs of Mohr for a day. Sorry no pictures of Belfast though I did see some of the protestant loyalist marchers gearing up by playing drum and flute for the celebration of the defeat of the Irish by William of Orange and symbolizes quite a bit of conflict and sectarian violence in Northern Ireland.</description></item><item><title>Pictures at Last!</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-18/</guid><description>Had a pretty cool tour through Cork today on an open top bus and got to visit Blarney castle. It’s a very nice area. The castle was a bit too busy to go up to the top, but I did visit the Dungeon cave. Mom I got your mail today from the post office thanks. And now I’ll leave you guys with pictures since I don’t have much else to say.</description></item><item><title>Ireland…Take two</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-16/</guid><description>so somewhere in my infinite wisdom I thought “Hey walk around ireland that’s a good idea”…well it’s not. You sweat a ton cause your so stinking out of shape and then if you do find somewhere to pitch a tent there you are in a very small space…with no lack of your own BO. Then you walk all day to somewhere just to find out that both your guidebook and your map of Ireland are wrong and there’s not been a hostel there for a couple of years, so you grab a bite to eat and begin to head for the edge of town to sneak a camp spot when it starts raining.</description></item><item><title>Neew yoork city</title><link>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://travelingbeard.com/posts/2008-06-10/</guid><description>Two words -flipping hot! Holy cow mamacita I’ve never sweat so much in my life. Mom, made it to the terminal. Everyone else more updates to follow</description></item></channel></rss>